what's up Savvy experts in today's video
we're getting into the top 10 life
insurance companies in the Philippines
once again all information in this video
is based off of our very valuable Source
grid pH the link to grit Peach's guide
on life insurance in the Philippines is
all linked Down Below in the description
to check out alright enough talk let's
get straight into it so first things
first we need to pin down how to
actually apply for life insurance as an
expat in the Philippines and so you're
gonna need to prepare the necessary
documents before you apply this includes
number one a current valid passport two
an alien certificate of registration
otherwise called an ACR card if you
don't have that and you're working in
the Philippines you'll need an alien
employment permit or if you're retired
in the Philippines you'll need to
present your srrv Visa ID which in srrb
Visa stands for a special resident
retirees visa and the third and last
thing you'll need to apply for life
insurance is a tin or a tax
identification number once you have all
of these things set you'll then choose
the life insurance company that fits
your needs and as suggested you should
go to your life insurance company's
office or website to ask for a financial
advisor to guide you along this whole
process from there you'll then choose a
life insurance type whether it's term
whole life or variable following that
you'll need to fill out an application
that involves details such as your
beneficiaries your family health history
so on and so forth on top of that
foreign Nationals are required to fill
out a background residential form and
lastly you'll set up a payment method
with your life insurance company you'll
receive your documents and you'll pay
your premiums based off of the plans
that you choose and now that we got that
settled let's get into the top 10 life
insurance companies in the Philippines
so at number one on our list we have the
approved Life Insurance Corporation of
the UK pro-life was founded in 1984 and
has headquarters across the world with
its main headquarter based in London
they offer a wide range of financial
products and services as well as Asset
Management Services in Asia this can be
a way for you not only to have life
insurance but also an extra income from
their services and aside from Life
Insurance products they also offer
health and Protection Services as you
can see in this graph the premium that
you pay per month depends on the assured
sum that you're going for of course life
insurance gets more expensive with age
so for those of you in your 50s looking
to get insured for a million pesos or
twenty thousand dollars your monthly
payments would be around seven to eight
thousand pesos per month and in dollars
that's 140 dollars to 160 dollars per
month it needs to say the rates and
premiums for higher Insurance coverages
increases from here moving on to life
insurance company number two we have Sun
Life Philippines founded in 1895 Sun
Life offers a wide range of financial
products from insurance wealth to Asset
Management there's multiple options to
fit your needs for starters Sun Life
offers insurance plans to fund your
children's education even while you're
gone they also have in a state
preservation plan that ensures that your
wealth and Legacy will we pass on to
your beneficiaries hassle-free so why
choose on life well Sun Life has
generated the most revenue from the
total premiums that they charge on their
policies in 2021 they've made over 45
million pesos in selling premiums that
said they've remained one of the most
profitable insurance companies in the
world but what does this mean for you
well this solidifies sunlife's ability
to not only take care and grow your
wealth but also to fulfill your goals
even while you're gone now at number
three we have the Philippine AXA Life
Insurance Corporation founded in 1962
Philippine AXA life insurance has been a
major player in the life insurance
industry headquartered in Makati City
their products range from educational
Health income protection Investments and
much more what's more is that Philippine
AXA is one of the most trusted life
insurance companies in the Philippines
that's because they've been offering
Financial Security to over 2 million
individuals Nationwide and they've
consistently been ranked as one of the
top 10 life insurance companies in the
Philippines now and number four on our
list we have FWD Life Insurance
Corporation FWD life is one of the
fastest growing Insurance firms in the
Philippines and so conveniently FWD
allows its customers to manage their
policies on their mobile app called tap
they offer a wide array of health and
life insurance plans as well as health
insurance plans paired with investment
products and what's unique about fwbd
life is that it also offers Financial
products that makes investments in US
Dollars now the fifth company we have on
our list is AIA Philippines American
life and general Corporation founded in
1947 Philippine American life in general
specializes in Life Insurance and
financial products these include
protection health and accident savings
education investment plans Wellness
programs and financial plans now for a
life insurance company number six we
have Manulife Philippines Manulife
Philippines is a financial company that
specializes in pension and education
investment medical employee security
corporate student personal accident
credit life and other insurance plans
with numerous products and packages to
choose from you may find the best plan
tailored to your needs moving on to life
insurance company number seven we have
BDO life which was formerly called
generali Pilipinas life BDO life offers
a host of Financial and Investment
Services that range from insurance
health education and other Financial
Services now at Insurance Company Number
Eight we have Alliance pnb life
insurance The Alliance Group in
partnership with the Philippine national
bank started providing life insurance
products in the Philippines in 2001.
originally headquartered in Germany
Alliance is globally recognized in the
financial services sector at number nine
on our list we have the BPI Phil M light
life Assurance Corporation established
in 1933 the company used to be known as
Ayala life Assurance corporated and so
BPI offers a wide range of financial
products and services this includes
savings Investments educational fun
retirement fund personal accident income
protection and much more now for the
10th and last life insurance company we
have that is United coconut Planters
life Assurance Corporation founded in
1966 ucpb specializes in life insurance
underwriting they offer services
covering protection education pension
and retirement and Memorial insurance
plans now the last topic that we'll
cover is how to find the best life
insurance company and policies deciding
on which insurance company to entrust
your hard-earned money is essential that
said there's a few key qualities to look
for when choosing the best life
insurance company first the company
should be listed as a licensed Insurance
firm second check the company's
background in the insurance industry
because ideally you should pick one with
an outstanding reputation and third
check the company's financial
performance if a company has high net
worth and high premium income this can
be good indicators of a high performing
and well-trusted life insurance company
and so there you have it Tabby expats
that wraps up the top 10 life insurance
companies in the Philippines if you
found this video to be of value feel
free to drop a like and comment down
below if you have any questions and so
thank you for watching Savvy expats and
I'll see you in the next video God bless
foreign
[Music]